Hello everyone
I'm September
I wonder if you've seen the KIMI K2.5 technical report
there's a very interesting piece of work
Agent Swarm
which translates to agent swarm
This feels like it could become a mainstream architecture in the agent direction in the future.
a mainstream architecture
Let's first review the traditional agent paradigm
This single-process model
It is essentially the agent's
in its early stages
The simplest model is a large language model plus tool calling.
Then, as the complexity of tasks increases
the dual-agent tower architecture emerged
and multi-process architectures
Of course, this is also related to
the model's own reasoning and planning capabilities
gradually enhanced to some extent
Dual-Agent collaboration
This model involves two agents
One is the planner
one is the executor
The planner is responsible for formulating a plan based on the specific task.
and the executor is responsible for invoking specific tools
to accomplish these plans
then the multi-agent architecture
I think there are two different patterns
The first type is the agent's AS as TOS
It is actually quite similar to the classic single-agent architecture
except that it treats an agent as
as a tool for use
Then, there is no interaction between the different sub-agents.
For instance, here this master agent
It is responsible for selecting different sub-agents based on your task.
int to complete these tasks
and different sub-agents
It is equipped with some callable tools
for example, this data analysis sub-agent
read, write, and edit
Then, uh, this network search agent
It can certainly use web search tools
or a tool for browser usage
The other mode is the directed graph pattern
different intelligent agents collaborate with each other
We typically use the LGO AF framework to build
This directed graph model of multi-agent architecture
Let's look at this example uh
This one is responsible for formulating the execution plan
This one is responsible for execution.
After the execution is completed
this one is responsible for verification or checking the results of its execution
whether there are any omissions or errors
After checking, uh
This EINT is responsible for updating the plan
After the update is completed, proceed with execution.
until all plans have been executed
eventually generates a complete report of the intermediate processes or the execution results
generate a comprehensive report
It is a model of this kind
and uh
The Agent Swarm mentioned in KIMI 2.5
Well, its purpose is to address the issue of execution efficiency
That is, when we execute sequentially
or when executing sequentially
especially when multiple tool calls are required
its execution efficiency is relatively low
and the agent swarm achieves this through parallel execution
to improve its execution efficiency
For example, if I want the model to help me search for ten
papers in three fields
If I execute it sequentially
it may need to invoke this uh three times
web search tool to perform searches
So if we use ENGINSWARM
this method of parallel search
then I just need to create a web search agent
and then distribute three tasks
These three tasks are executed in parallel
By doing so, it can significantly reduce
execution time
Let's take a look at the architecture of Agent Swarm
This is from the KIMI 2.5 paper.
Its composition consists of a coordinator
It is responsible for creating sub-agents
and distributes tasks to different sub-agents.
It can distribute tasks among different sub-EDTs.
can also distribute different tasks to the same sub-agent
to distribute different tasks
Here we can see this coordinator
It is actually equipped with several tools
One is a tool for creating and building sub-agents.
one is for distributing tasks
as well as search and browser usage
using these basic tools uh
The difference between it and ZEGA is that
It has these two tools.
because it needs to create this shot and assign tasks
then the diameter does not have these two tools
The Diameter actually only has some basic ones
such as search and browsing tools
Then when the coordinator creates sub-agents
the role of a sub-agent
which means
The system prompt is specified by the coordinator itself.
then when distributing tasks
it will specifically select a certain professional process
and assign specific task descriptions to the selected professional process
The purpose of this is for some complex tasks
needs to be distributed
parallel execution by sub-agents
to improve the efficiency of task completion
So it relies on creating designated
as well as the two tools for task distribution
to complete this step
However, for some simple tasks, uh,
It can solve it by itself
It doesn't need to distribute this task anymore
At this point, it can utilize some basic tools
such as search
and the browser, etc.
to complete these relatively simple tasks
So how can we improve the model's dynamic scheduling capability?
The paper proposes a reinforcement learning method
called parallel agent reinforcement learning
Its reward consists of three parts.
Well, this reward is designed to encourage the model to perform concurrent scheduling.
The main optimization is to
the model's dynamic scheduling capability
which encourages the model to create more subprocesses
to complete this task
As for this reward,
It is to prevent the model from pursuing more rewards
and creating meaningless agent towers
in order to prevent a kind of reward hacking behavior
Because our first reward is designed to encourage the model to perform concurrent
scheduling professional skills
This may result in a situation
the model attempts to obtain more of this reward
then it will create many professional agents
but uh these agents between
many of them may be useless
So this part is added
It depends on whether the created subtasks are successfully completed.
and through this, it restricts the model
prompt it to create more useful subprocesses
Ultimately, this reward is obtained upon task completion.
This is the main objective we aim to optimize.
Then during the training process
These two parameters will dynamically reset to zero
as the training progresses
the model's ability to dynamically schedule instructions
is becoming increasingly stronger
In the later stages of training, the focus should be on optimizing the model
the ability to accomplish the primary goal
which is the ability to accomplish the specific tasks assigned to us
because this is our main optimization direction
Additionally, during training, the agent is frozen.
This is done to address a credit assignment issue
and the issue of training instability
because in reinforcement learning
Outcome-based rewards are typically very sparse.
then this outcome reward
How to allocate it to different A-keys?
It's actually a very difficult thing to do
because different IH
Because different agents have varying levels of performance
and even the same agent may perform well or poorly at different execution steps
Um
If the result reward
evenly distributed among these different professions
Well, it's actually not very appropriate.
So since it's difficult to distribute
Then simply don't split it
then simply freeze all the agents
only optimize this one
coordinator
Because intuitively speaking,
As long as this thing is optimized well enough
then it decomposes tasks and
its ability to distribute tasks becomes very strong
As long as it breaks down tasks effectively
that is, um, his description of individual subtasks is sufficiently clear
so that the subprocesses can be more clear
clearly understand the requirement
At the same time, it can also improve the execution success rate of the child process.
So it indirectly optimizes in this way
optimize the execution effect of this shot
Because these two are essentially the same model
it's just referring to
an intermediate checkpoint of a training node
We can also feel that this Agent Swarm
It actually looks very similar to multi-agent processes
Actually, it belongs to one implementation method of multi-process systems.
It's particularly similar to the async-to approach in multi-agent systems,
a main agent is responsible for task distribution
to schedule different worker processes
However, it does differ from this approach in some ways.
Um, generally in a multi-agent architecture
We create these professional agents ourselves, right?
through different system prompts
to assign different roles to the model for completing specific tasks
However, in an agent swarm,
it is actually created by the model itself
The model performs task decomposition and distribution based on the specific task,
task decomposition and distribution
It will then autonomously initialize some
some agents adapted to different subtasks
then there's the agent swarm
it can create multiple identical agents to execute tasks in parallel
In fact, we can also achieve this through rules combined with prompts
to achieve an effect similar to that of Agent Swarm
but in KIMI 2.5
it has transformed this capability into the model
its native capability
is definitely better than us constraining it through some prompts
a much better effect
Next is the coordinator
The two additional tools it has
One is the tool for creating A1, and the other is the tool for creating child A processes
It requires a parameter
which is the system prompt for
The current sub-agent is used to define its role and capabilities.
Then there's another tool for task distribution, um,
Its function is to call the previously created agent
and then assign different tasks to these agents
We can see it has two parameters
One is agent
This is the instruction for which sub-agent should be called
and this prompt is the specific task description given to the agent
task description
OK, that's all for today's video
If you enjoyed the content, feel free to follow
You're also welcome to discuss and exchange ideas in the comment section.
Bye